Guide to the Gene Federico Papers, 1918-2003 and undated, bulk 1951-1991 RL.00383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Graphic Design Series, 1934-2002 and undated, bulk 1940-1997
  - By Federico
    - Client catalogs/brochures
      - Museum of Art, Science and Industry (Fairfield, Connecticut): promotional brochure, 1959 (Box 4)
      - New York City Ballet, undated (Box 4)
      - UCLA Extension/Summer Programs, 1990-1991 and 1993 (Box 4)
    - Concepts and sketches
      - AIGA (American Institute for Graphic Arts), undated (Box 4)
      - Art Directors Club: entry form, undated (Box 4)
      - Components and research - Various, circa 1984 and undated (Box 4)
      - Connections design, undated (Box 4)
      - Federico Design, 1989 (Box 4)
      - GUD LUK horseshoe design, undated (Box 4)
      - Jan the Miller: The Miller's Tale, undated (Box 4)
      - Mercury by Giovanni Bologna (photostats), undated (Box 4)
        [3 images from the New York Public Library Picture Collection.]
      - National Association of Art Services, undated (Box 4)
      - The Only Real Cotton is 100% Cotton, undated (Box 4)
      - Open for Business!, undated (Box 4)
      - Pierre Hotel, undated (Box 4)
      - Portrait of Jenny film promotion, undated (Box 4)
        [Design for poster/promotion for film produced by the Selznik Studio, starring actors Jennifer Jones, Joseph Cotten, Ethel Barrymore, Lillian Gish, and Cecil Kellaway.]
      - RCA Records, undated (Box 4)
      - Shurlock Homes, undated (Box 4)
      - 7th Educational Graphic Arts Exposition, 1959 (Box 4)
      - Various, 1978 and undated, 2 folders. (Box 4)
    - Cover designs (Box 5)
      - Annual reports
        - GTE, 1987 (Box 5)
        - National Patent Development Corporation, 1966 (Box 5)
      - Book covers
        - Beyond Human Ken: 21 Startling Stories of Science Fiction and Fantasy (Ed. Judith Merril), undated (Box 5)
        - Christian Science: Its Encounter with American Culture (Robert Peel), undated (Box 5)
        - Doubleday titles (fiction and nonfiction) - Various, undated (Box 5)
        - Doubleday Anchor series, undated (Box 5)
          [Includes several titles: Decisions in Syrcause; Class, Citizenship, and Social Development; The Radical Right; Socialist Thought.]
        - The Emancipation Proclamation (John Hope Franklin), undated (Box 5)
        - Film Form (Sergei Eisenstein), undated (Box 5)
        - The Human Condition (Hannah Arendt), undated (Box 5)
        - I Played Rhythm (Eddie Condon), undated (Box 5)
        - Lament for William (Charlotte Murray Russell), undated (Box 5)
        - Politics of Population (William Petersen), undated (Box 5)
        - The Trend Is Up (Anthony West), undated (Box 5)
        - Winning Without War (Amitai Etzioni), undated (Box 5)
        - 64th Art Directors Annual (ADC Publications), undated (Box 5)
        - Various, undated (Box 5)
      - Magazines/Journals
        - AK News (Abbott Kimball Company), 1940 Dec. 23 (Box 5)
        - Architectural Forum, 1947-1948 and undated (Box 5)
        - Art Direction, 1958 Nov. (Box 5)
        - Interiors and Industrial Design, 1949 May (Box 5)
        - Liberty magazine concepts, 1948 and undated (Box 5)
        - Measure, 1947 Apr. (Box 5)
        - The Nation, 1950 Dec. (Box 5)
        - The Other Side: Magazine of Justice Rooted in Discipleship, 1991 Jan./Feb. (Box 5)
        - Spectrum (Pfizer), undated (Box 5)
      - Record covers
        - Compass Records ( Romeo and Juliet, Prokofieff; 24 Selections, classic to jazz), undated (Box 5)
        - Epic Records, undated (Box 5)
        - Lukas Foss, A Parable of Death (Columbia Records), undated (Box 5)
        - Various (Columbia, Decca), 1947 and undated (Box 5)
    - Illustrations
      - Harper's Bazaar: Felicia Gizycka stories, 1942 Dec. (Box 5)
      - Liberty magazine, The Women Across the Hall piece, 1948 Apr. (Box 5)
      - One Of Us Must Die, Edmund Gilligan essay, 1962 Sept. 8 (Box 5)
      - Saturday Evening Post: The Girl Who Hated Men / John Reese story, 1962 (Box 5)
        [Includes photocopies of letters congratulating Federico; see Professional Files: Correspondence, Saturday Evening Post, 1962 for original correspondence.]
    - Letterhead/Logo (Box 6)
      - Letterhead
        - Airborne Billboards, Inc., undated (Box 6)
        - Art Directors Club, undated (Box 6)
        - Art Kane Studio, undated (Box 6)
        - Bishop Color Inc., undated (Box 6)
        - Bob Fischer, undated (Box 6)
        - Brouillard Communications, undated (Box 6)
        - Chance 3 Productions, undated (Box 6)
        - Cinema 16, undated (Box 6)
        - Douglas D. Simon Advertising, undated (Box 6)
        - Irving E. Elfenbein, undated (Box 6)
        - Federico - Personal/Family, undated (Box 6)
        - Forma Art Associates, Ltd. (Films), undated (Box 6)
        - Gilbert Paper Company - promotional packet, 1978 (Box 6)
        - Harold Becker, undated (Box 6)
        - Joseph B. Hinerfeld, undated (Box 6)
        - Lord Geller Federico Einstein, undated (Box 6)
        - M. Sokolsky, undated (Box 6)
        - Martin (Alice Manougain), undated (Box 6)
        - Murray Duitz, undated (Box 6)
        - Plums letterhead packet, 1978 (Box 6)
          [Includes letterhead designs by Mo Leibowitz; Loucks Atelier; Burns, Cooper, Hynes Limited; George Tscherny, Inc.; Casado, Ltd.; Lord, Geller, Federico, Inc.; Charles White III and Friends; The Richards Group Inc.]
        - Robert L. Brooks, undated (Box 6)
        - Secor Marketing, Inc., undated (Box 6)
        - Ted Croner Studio, undated (Box 6)
        - Toni Ficalora, undated (Box 6)
        - William Bell, undated (Box 6)
          [Includes 8.5" X 11.5" photostat of large-format business card.]
        - William Helburn Productions, undated (Box 6)
        - WPIX FM, undated (Box 6)
        - Various (letterhead, business cards), undated (Box 6)
      - Logos
        - American Ballet Theatre, undated (Box 6)
        - Sunlight Pictures Corp., undated (Box 6)
        - Thunderbolt and Lightfoot film logo, circa early 1970s (Box 6)
        - Various, undated (Box 6)
          [Includes logo concepts for Supima Cotton and Smith College.]
    - Posters
      - American Ballet Theatre, undated (Box 6)
      - Art Directors Club - 39th Annual exhibition, 1959-1960 (Box 6)
      - Art exhibits, 1937 and 1980 (Box 6)
      - Dsseldorf (City poster competition), 1951 and undated (Box 6)
        [Federico received second prize in the competition. Folder includes correspondence/guidelines related to the competition, in addition to design concepts.]
      - Eastern Native Seed Conservancy (Tomato Festival), 2001 and undated (Box 6)
      - Hiram Halle Memorial Library: 40th Anniversary, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Illustrators XII, 1968 (Box 6)
      - Kimberly Colors Collection, undated (Box 6)
      - Napoli poster collection (postcards), 1984-1986 and undated (Box 6)
      - New York City's Hudson Celebration, 1959 (Box 6)
      - Observatoire International Des Prisons, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Reflections: Pound Ridge Garden Club, undated (Box 6)
      - Tileston & Hollingsworth Company, undated (Box 6)
      - UCLA Extension, 1990 (Box 6)
      - A 70-Year Odyssey (Federico biography in NYC), undated (Box 6)
      - Various (AIDS, Love Mother Earth, prisons), 1967, 1996, 1998 and undated (Box 6)
    - Transparencies (Box 7)
      - Royal Composing Room: Gene Federico: The Art Director's Art Director article, circa 1987 (Box 7)
      - Various, undated (Box 7)
        [Includes transparencies for Lord Geller Federico Einstein clients/promotion, N the Big Inning Was the Word design, and Push Pin design. Related materials included in Additional designs above.]
    - Typographic materials
      - The New Yorker, undated (Box 7)
      - Original designs, undated (Box 7)
      - PM Typography, 1984 and undated (Box 7)
      - Typeface samples
        - American Type Founders Company fonts (body shapes), undated (Box 7)
        - Decorative initials, undated (Box 7)
        - Various, 1949, 1953 and undated (Box 7)
  - By other designers/artists, 1934-2002 and undated
    [Arranged alphabetically, artist by last name.]
    - Bachwitz, Atelier: Album Blouses Nouvelles: Chic Parisien, undated (Box 7)
      [Historical publication, undated. Fashion designs with introductory text in English, French, Italian, and German.]
    - Benrimo, Tom
      - Articles/profiles (on Tom and Dorothy Benrimo), 1960, 1967, 1984 and undated (Box 7)
      - Designs, 1934 and undated (Box 7)
      - Exhibition catalog (organized by Fort Worth Art Center and Valley House Gallery), 1964 (Box 7)
      - Lectures and notes, undated (Box 7)
    - ERGO (portfolio of various artists, including Andy Warhol, Bob Sullivan, Jerome Martin ), undated (Box 7)
    - Gluck, Nathan, circa 1990-1999 and 2002 (Box 7)
    - Gorbaty, Norman - portfolio, undated (Box 7)
    - Heartfield, John (anti-Nazi photographer), undated (Box 7)
    - Larimer, Bob, undated (Box 7)
    - Lubalin, Herb: Iconochrestomathy, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Reiss, Winold, 1996 and undated (Box 7)
    - Steinberg, Saul and Hedda Sterne, 1951 (Box 7)
    - Varisco, Tom, undated (Box 7)
    - Warhol, Andy - memorial (articles, images), 1987 (Box 7)
    - Various, 1940, 1989, 1996 and undated (Box 7)
- Advertising Campaigns Series, 1937-1991 and undated, bulk 1953-1991
  Contains client research reports, advertisement clippings and proofs, advertisement concepts and sketches, and scrapbooks of advertisements. Materials represent a wide variety of American and European clients, with a focus on women's apparel and cosmetics, home furnishings, business/finance and new technology. Significant clients include: Christian Dior, Disney hats, Elizabeth Arden, Goldman Sachs, IBM, L'Aiglon Apparel, Magee Carpets and Rugs, Napier, The New Yorker, and Woman's Day. For preservation purposes, mounted and unmounted advertisements have been boxed separately, under the category Clippings and proofs. Arranged alphabetically by format, therein alphabetically by client.
  - Client Reports (Box 8)
    - American Cancer Society: Anti-Cigarette Television Messages, 1967 (Box 8)
    - IBM (Problem-Solving and Special Events campaigns, etc.), 1961-1962, 1983 (Box 8)
    - Napier (costume jewelry), 1978 (Box 8)
  - Clippings and proofs
    - Unmounted advertisements
      - Air India, 1964 (Box 8)
        [Features Federico in advertisement photo.]
      - American Elegance, undated (Box 8)
      - Arthur Andersen, 1991 (Box 8)
      - B. Blumenthal & Co.: Le Chic and La Mode buttons, undated (Box 8)
      - Ban-Lon knitwear (Joseph Bancroft & Sons, Co.), 1964, 1966 and undated (Box 8)
      - Benton & Bowles, 1960 (Box 8)
      - Bohn, undated (Box 8)
        [An undated and uncredited historical advertisement. Features the tag-line Only a Bohn is Bohn-Dry!, seemingly for an early mimeograph machine.]
      - Borg Fabrics
        - Assorted products (Borglura, Modelia), 1958-1959 and undated (Box 8)
        - Borgana coats, 1956 and undated (Box 8)
        - Borglura brochure, circa 1950s (Box 8)
      - Caprolan, 1966 (Box 8)
      - Chemstrand Nylon, 1954-1955 and undated (Box 8)
      - Christian Dior (Wamsutta linens, Gross jewelry, Wyner), 1956, circa mid 1980s and undated (Box 8)
      - Columbia Records: Columbia Masterworks, 1960 and undated (Box 8)
      - Container Corporation of America: Disraeli advertisement, undated (Box 8)
        [See also Advertising Campaigns: Magazine Spreads, Time Magazine and The New Yorker ad placement.]
      - Cool-Whip, undated (Box 8)
      - Corn Silk, 1965 (Box 8)
      - Dauphine (petites), 1959 (Box 8)
      - Disney hats, 1951 and undated (Box 8)
      - Doubleday Dictionary, undated (Box 8)
      - Duchess (dresses), undated (Box 8)
      - Einiger Fabrics, 1956 and undated (Box 8)
      - Elektra Records (Judy Collins, The Doors, The Incredible String Band), circa late 1960s (Box 8)
      - Elizabeth Arden
        - Arden for Men, undated (Box 8)
        - Cosmetics, 1972, 1979 and undated (Box 8)
        - Parfums Lagerfeld, 1978 (Box 8)
      - Ethiopian Airlines, undated (Box 8)
      - Faberg: Straw Hat perfume, 1972 (Box 8)
      - Famous-Barr Company: Pandora footwear, undated (Box 8)
      - Firestone Plastics Company, undated (Box 8)
      - French Government Tourist Office, undated (Box 8)
      - Gay Gibson (women's apparel), 1956, 1958, 1960 and undated (Box 8)
      - Germaine-Monteil, 1980 (Box 8)
      - Glass Container Manufacturers Institute, 1963-1964 and undated (Box 8)
      - Hart's Seeds, undated (Box 8)
      - Harvey's Bristol Cream, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
      - Helena Rubinstein (cosmetics), undated (Box 8)
      - Hennessy (champagne and cognac), undated (Box 8)
      - Hilton International, circa 1976-1977 and undated (Box 8)
      - Hollander Furs, 1951 (Box 8)
      - Hollywood Diet Bread, undated (Box 8)
      - IBM
        - American Expressionism Exhibition, undated (Box 8)
          [Advertisement for art exhibit sponsored by IBM, held at Boston Institute of Contemporary Art.]
        - Products, 1961-1962, circa 1964-1965 and undated (Box 8)
      - Innocenti Corporation: Lambretta scooter, 1954 (Box 8)
      - Jamaica, 1978 (Box 8)
      - Jana (handbags), 1953 and undated (Box 8)
      - Jane Irwill (knitwear), undated (Box 8)
      - Jo Collins (women's apparel), 1956-1958 and undated (Box 8)
      - Kaufman Carpet Co., Inc, 1949 and undated (Box 8)
      - Killington, Vermont, 1970 and undated (Box 8)
      - Kislav (gloves), undated (Box 8)
      - Kleinert's (undergarments), undated (Box 8)
      - L. Bamberger & Co., 1941-1942 (Box 9)
      - Lady Pepperell
        - Proofs, 1964-1965 and undated (Box 9)
        - Newspaper, undated (Box 9)
      - L'Aiglon Apparel, Inc.
        - General L'Aiglon
          - Color photocopies, 1955-1959 (Box 9)
          - Newspaper, 1955-1959 and undated (Box 9)
          - Proofs, 1956-1958 and undated (Box 9)
            [Includes color photocopies of original proofs.]
        - Jeanne d'Arc
          - 1955-1959 and undated (Box 9)
          - Newspaper, 1958-1959 and undated (Box 9)
      - Lauffer (glassware), 1969 and 1973 (Box 9)
      - Life magazine, 1968 (Box 9)
      - Life Savers, undated (Box 9)
      - Lisner (jewelry), 1956-1959 and undated (Box 9)
      - Lord Geller Federico Einstein, undated (Box 9)
      - Magee (carpets and rugs), 1950 and undated (Box 9)
      - Main Street Fashions, undated (Box 9)
      - Max Factor, undated (Box 9)
      - Milliken Fabrics, 1959 and undated (Box 9)
      - Modern Library, undated (Box 9)
      - Mona Lisa: Triomphe girdle, undated (Box 9)
      - Napier, 1979-1988 and undated (Box 9)
      - National Cotton Council, 1957-1959 and undated (Box 9)
      - Necchi (sewing machine), 1953 (Box 9)
      - The New Yorker, 1978-1988 and undated (Box 9)
      - Pan Am, undated (Box 9)
      - Parfums Chevalier Garde, undated (Box 9)
      - Parfums de Corday (Trapze, Toujours Moi), 1958 and undated (Box 9)
      - Peggy Sage (nailpolish), 1946 and undated (Box 9)
      - Pepperell Manufacturing Company, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
      - Phillips-Jones Corporation: Van Heusen, undated (Box 9)
      - Pioneer-Moss (photoengravers): Exhibitions/Awards promotions, 1970 and undated (Box 9)
      - Reva (handbags), undated (Box 9)
      - Revlon (Nail Enamel Corporation), undated (Box 9)
      - Schieffelin & Co.: Appleton Jamaica Rum, undated (Box 9)
      - Schumacher, undated (Box 9)
      - Strathmore (books, stationery), undated (Box 9)
      - Supima Cotton, circa 1950s and undated (Box 9)
      - Sutra Sunfilter Cream, undated (Box 9)
      - Symon's Art Service, undated (Box 9)
      - Tanner, 1973 and undated (Box 9)
      - Tecnique Color-Tone, 1962-1963 and undated (Box 9)
      - Thomas Strahan Company (draperies), undated (Box 9)
      - Toni Ficalora, 1959 (Box 9)
      - Town and Country magazine, 1940 (Box 9)
      - Vassarette (nightgowns, lingerie), 1981-1982 and undated (Box 9)
      - Vivitar, 1978 (Box 9)
      - Volupt jewelers, 1940 (Box 9)
      - Waverly, undated (Box 9)
      - Wear-Right (gloves), 1952-1955 and undated (Box 9)
      - Woman's Day, 1953-1955 and undated (Box 9)
      - Wool Bureau, undated (Box 9)
      - WOR (radio), 1937, 1939 and undated (Box 9)
      - Wyner (knitwear): Sag-No-Mor wool jersey
        - Dior, circa 1950s (Box 9)
        - Other designers (Anne Klein, Marion McCoy, Maurice Rentner), 1957 and undated (Box 9)
      - Zenith Movado, 1973 and undated (Box 9)
      - Various
        - Multiple/Unidentified clients, 1970 and undated (Box 9)
        - Newspaper, 1954-1991 and undated (Box 9)
    - Mounted advertisements (Box 10)
      - Austro-Daimler bicycles, undated (Box 10)
      - B. Blumenthal & Co.
        - La Mode buttons, undated (Box 10)
        - Le Chic buttons, undated (Box 10)
      - Bell's Scotch Whisky (Arthur Bell & Sons, Ltd.), 1961 (Box 10)
      - Borg Fabrics, circa 1955 (Box 10)
      - Christian Dior
        - Gross jewelry, circa mid-1980s (Box 10)
        - Wamsutta linens, circa mid-1980s and undated (Box 10)
        - Wyner, circa mid 1950s (Box 10)
        - Various, circa mid 1980s (Box 10)
      - Corn Silk (cosmetics), 1965 (Box 10)
      - Cotton Producers Institute, undated (Box 10)
      - Elektra Records (Judy Collins, The Doors, Tim Buckley), circa 1960s (Box 10)
      - Einiger, circa 1950s (Box 10)
      - Elizabeth Arden, 1971-1972 and undated (Box 10)
      - Harvey's Bristol Cream (John Harvey & Sons Ltd.), 1962-1963 (Box 10)
      - Helena Rubinstein (cosmetics), undated (Box 10)
      - Hennessy Cognac (Shieffelin & Co.), undated (Box 10)
      - IBM (typewriters), 1962-1963 and undated (Box 10)
      - Killington, Vermont - Skiing, 1970, 1972 and undated (Box 10)
      - Lady Pepperell: It's a print, print, print, print world! campaign, 1965 and undated (Box 10)
      - L'Aiglon Apparel, Inc., circa 1950s (Box 11)
      - Lauffer (glassware): Auberge design, 1973 (Box 11)
      - Lisner & Co. jewelry, 1956 and 1959 (Box 11)
      - Magee carpets and rugs
        - Busy As Bees campaign, undated (Box 11)
        - Thanksgiving, 1950 (Box 11)
        - Various, undated (Box 11)
      - Milliken Fabrics, circa 1957 and undated (Box 11)
      - Napier, 1983, 1986 and undated (Box 11)
      - The New Yorker, 1972, 1984 and undated (Box 11)
      - Parfums de Corday: Trapze, undated (Box 11)
      - Schumacher fabrics, undated (Box 11)
      - Stiffel, undated (Box 11)
      - Tanner (women's apparel), undated (Box 11)
      - Tecnique Color Tone (hair dye), circa 1962-1963 (Box 11)
      - Wear-Right (gloves), undated (Box 11)
      - Woman's Day, 1953 (Box 11)
        [Rare page proof of famed She's got to go out to get Woman's Day bicycle advertisement.]
  - Concepts and sketches (Box 12)
    - Alfa Romeo, 1988 and undated (Box 12)
    - American Ballet Theatre, undated (Box 12)
    - Arthur Andersen, circa 1991 (Box 12)
    - B. Blumenthal & Co.: Le Chic buttons, undated (Box 12)
    - Bell's Scotch Whisky (Arthur Bell & Sons, Ltd.), 1961 and undated (Box 12)
    - Benton & Bowles, circa 1960 (Box 12)
    - Borg, undated (Box 12)
    - Caribiwi slogans, undated (Box 12)
    - Chandon champagne, 1989 and undated (Box 12)
    - Christian Dior: Wyner collection, Sag-No-Moor jersey, undated (Box 12)
    - Container Corporation of America: Disraeli advertisement, undated (Box 12)
    - Corn Silk (cosmetics), undated (Box 12)
    - Disney Hats, undated (Box 12)
    - D'Orsay, undated (Box 12)
    - The Economist, undated (Box 12)
    - Emeraude, undated (Box 12)
    - Fondera cashmere, undated (Box 12)
    - Gay Gibson, undated (Box 12)
    - Goldman Sachs, undated (Box 12)
    - Hennessy, undated (Box 12)
    - IBM
      - Brochure, undated (Box 12)
      - Pencil in a knot design, 1988 (Box 12)
      - Various, undated (Box 12)
    - Jana (handbags), circa 1955 (Box 12)
    - Killington, Vermont, 1972 and undated (Box 12)
    - Lady Pepperell, undated (Box 12)
    - Life Savers, undated, 2 folders. (Box 12)
    - Mercury Records, undated (Box 12)
    - Modecraft (coats): Builders All, Americans All campaign, circa 1950s (Box 12)
      [Features President Dwight D. Eisenhower, highlights True Americanism vs. Un-Americanism.]
    - Mumm Sparkling Wine, 1987 and undated (Box 12)
    - Napier, undated (Box 12)
    - NE Airlines, undated (Box 12)
    - The New Yorker, undated (Box 12)
      [Features Woody Allen advertisement.]
    - Parfums de Corday, undated (Box 12)
    - Pauline Trigre (raincoats), undated (Box 12)
    - Pine Bros. (cough drops), undated (Box 12)
    - Popov Vodka, undated (Box 12)
    - Prince Spaghetti, undated (Box 12)
    - Renault Dauphine, undated (Box 12)
    - Rob & Burns Cigarillos, undated (Box 12)
    - Sony, undated (Box 12)
    - Tecnique Color-Tone (hair dye), circa 1962-1963 (Box 12)
    - Tomorrow perfume, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Valentino perfume, undated (Box 12)
    - Versace, undated (Box 12)
    - Woman's Day: You've got to go out to buy... campaign, 1953 and undated (Box 12)
    - Woodfield Country Club, undated (Box 12)
    - Various/unidentified, undated (Box 12)
  - Magazine spreads, 1942, 1957, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook, circa mid-1940s to early 1960s (Box 12)
    [Includes primarily advertisement clippings and proofs. Clients represented include: Architectural Forum; B. Blumenthal & Co.: Le Mode and Le Chic buttons; D'Orsay; Disney hats; Elizabeth Arden; Firestone: Contro Elastic Yarn; Kaufman Carpet Co.; Kislav gloves; Kleinert's (undergarments); Magee Carpets & Rugs; Peggy Sage cosmetics; and Symon's Art Service. Also includes two graphic design items (exhibition announcement and record cover design).]
- Photographs and Negatives Series, circa 1939-2001 and undated, bulk 1951-1996
  Contains photographs and negatives relating to Federico's professional work in advertising and graphic design, as well as family and personal images, dating from World War II until the late 1990s. Photographs are divided into four categories - "Advertisements," "Graphic design," "Of Federico (Business)" and "Personal/Family" - and include both color and black and white images. Negatives are divided into three categories - "Advertisements," "Graphic design," and "Of Federico (Business)" - and include negative strips from contact sheets. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Photographs (Box 13)
    - Advertisements
      - Advertising shoots, 1963 and undated (Box 13)
      - Air India, circa 1964
        [Gene Federico featured in photographs and final advertisement. For advertisement proof, see Box 8: Advertising Campaigns Series, Clippings and proofs (unmounted), Air India, 1964.]
        - Contact sheets (Box 13)
        - Enlargement (Box 13)
      - Albert Einstein (for Vogue), undated (Box 13)
      - Chandon champagne: television storyboards, undated (Box 13)
      - Emeraude, undated (Box 13)
      - Glass (for Glass Container Manufacturer's Institute), 1963 (Box 13)
      - Harvey's
        - Bristol Cream, circa 1963 (Box 13)
        - Sherry, undated (Box 13)
      - Hennessy, undated (Box 13)
      - IBM, undated (Box 13)
      - The New Yorker magazine, 1979 and undated (Box 13)
      - Parfums de Corday: Toujours Moi perfume, undated (Box 13)
      - Seagram's Gin, undated (Box 13)
        [Features Gene Federico.]
      - Tanner apparel: It's a Love, It's Tanner campaign, undated (Box 13)
      - Teacher's Scotch, undated (Box 13)
      - Woman's Day magazine, 1953 (Box 13)
      - Women's apparel - various, undated (Box 13)
      - Various (miscellaneous babies), undated (Box 13)
    - Graphic design
      - Authenticolor promotion, undated (Box 13)
      - Career highlights, 2001 (Box 13)
      - Dusseldorf poster design, circa 1951 (Box 13)